<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on Blog</title>
    <link>https://albertogrespan.com/tags/Jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 10:00:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://albertogrespan.com/tags/Jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Hugo</title>
      <link>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 10:00:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</author>
      <guid>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m writing my first blog post generated by Hugo. Hugo is static site generator written in Go. A couple of months ago (maybe more) I decided to move my personal blog from Jekyll to Hugo out of curiosity. Yes, Hugo is indeed much faster and has a lot of great features, but it lacks some things that Jekyll provided (at least for me), such as ad hoc Sass integration, syntax highlighting with Rouge, and automatic deploys to GitHub Pages, either way I decided to dig into Hugo, read the documentation on some of the core parts, and used the migration tool to move my posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Jekyll with Mina and rbenv</title>
      <link>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/deploying-jekyll-with-mina-and-rbenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</author>
      <guid>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/deploying-jekyll-with-mina-and-rbenv/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to show how to deploy a Jekyll site using Mina and it will not show how to serve the site with NGINX or Apache or install any dependencies like Ruby or rbenv on the server.
Even though we are not focusing in the things we mentioned above we&amp;rsquo;ll need a running machine them installed:
Ruby managed from rbenv NGINX or Apache If deploying from a private repo a new ssh keypair Installing Mina As Mina is just a gem we will use the gem command to install it or just add it to your Gemfile and bundle it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rake tasks &amp; Jekyll posts</title>
      <link>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/rake-tasks-and-jekyll-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</author>
      <guid>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/rake-tasks-and-jekyll-posts/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr use Rake tasks to create drafts/posts in Jekyll.
Creating a draft or a new post is a repetitive task. If you are like me and often forget about things you probably need some automation in your life; if you don&amp;rsquo;t, you can use this and start forgetting.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about some Rake tasks I use that help me create and publish drafts for my Jekyll blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I did this site using Jekyll and GitHub pages</title>
      <link>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/jekyll-github-pages-blog-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alberto@albertogrespan.com (Alberto Grespan)</author>
      <guid>https://albertogrespan.com/blog/jekyll-github-pages-blog-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>note: This post is deprecated by newer versions of Jekyll. You can probably summarize all this post with a jekyll new command.
So, How I did this Jekyll site? This site is runing on GitHub Pages and is using Jekyll for the layouts and blog posts. In this post I will guide you through the steps for you to build your own site using Jekyll.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning what&amp;rsquo;s Jekyll?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
