<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nginx on Blog</title>
    <link>http://albertogrespan.com/tags/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nginx on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://albertogrespan.com/tags/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Jekyll with Mina and rbenv</title>
      <link>http://albertogrespan.com/blog/deploying-jekyll-with-mina-and-rbenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://albertogrespan.com/blog/deploying-jekyll-with-mina-and-rbenv/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to show how to deploy a Jekyll site using Mina and it will not show how to serve the site with NGINX or Apache or install any dependencies like Ruby or rbenv on the server.
Even though we are not focusing in the things we mentioned above we&amp;rsquo;ll need a running machine them installed:
 Ruby managed from rbenv NGINX or Apache If deploying from a private repo a new ssh keypair  Installing Mina As Mina is just a gem we will use the gem command to install it or just add it to your Gemfile and bundle it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running multiple domains or subdomains in NGINX using Server Blocks in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://albertogrespan.com/blog/running-multiple-domains-or-subdomains-in-nginx-with-server-blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://albertogrespan.com/blog/running-multiple-domains-or-subdomains-in-nginx-with-server-blocks/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wonder; how can I have multiple domains or subdomains pointing to different projects but all of them are in just one server? well&amp;hellip;
This will be a very simple tutorial for doing that, with NGINX.
tutorial tasks:  Creating or pointing domains/subdomains to the server&amp;rsquo;s IP address Setup NGINX Create a directory to keep the project Change folder permissions Create a simple html page to display Create a new Server Block with your domain or subdomain Setup and link the Server Block Restart NGINX  1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>